Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Previously on The West Wing:
Mr. President?
GW, move, move!
Josh, didn't you hear me shouting
for you? I need a doctor.
-His pulse ox is 92 on 15 liters.
-I need to get to New Hampshire.
Come to Nashua, New Hampshire,
Thursday and hear Jed Bartlet speak.
I work for Hoynes.
-Come to Nashua Thursday night.
-Why?
That's what sons do for old
friends of their father's.
If I see the real thing,
should I tell you?
-You won't have to.
-Why?
-You got a bad poker face.
-Two shooters.
We got them,
but there was a signal.
-There was somebody on the ground?
-White male. 20, 25, maybe 5'10".
Deputy White House chief
of staff, Joshua Lyman...
...is currently undergoing extensive
surgery to repair a collapsed lung...
...and to remove a bullet that remains
lodged in his thoracic region.
For an update on his condition,
let's go live to Lynn Blakley...
... who 's standing by
at George Washington Hospital.
Wait, we 're not going there just yet.
Now, I'm being told that authorities
are reporting another gunshot victim....
-FBl.
-Let me see those hands!
-Police.
-Hold it right there.
-Get down.
-Police. Right there.
-Police. Freeze!
-Throw those hands up.
-Get down on the ground now!
-Get down.
-Secret Service.
-I said, get down, now!
Don't move.
We're confirming now that a suspect
has been taken into custody...
...and is being questioned
by federal law enforcement.
At this time, we cannot...
...we are not releasing any information
whatsoever about the suspect.
C.J., can you tell us anything?
His name, where he's from, ethnicity...
...if you guys suspect a motive?
I can tell you all those things...
... because when I said we weren't
releasing information...
... I meant, except his name, his address,
and what we think his motive was.
I am releasing the name
of Stephanie Abbott.
A-B-B-O-T-T,
of Silver Spring, Maryland...
...who was in the crowd and sustained
an injury to the left femur...
...which is the thigh bone.
The president remains in stable
condition in the recovery room...
...and is expected to be released
some time Wednesday.
Josh Lyman is now in his
sixth hour of surgery...
... to repair a collapsed lung and
a ruptured pulmonary artery.
We won 't have an update on him
until the procedure is complete...
... which they expect won 't be
for another six or eight hours.
We 'll keep you updated in the
next hour. Thank you very much.
C.J., what about the conference?
Ma'am, doe's the president
know they've arrested a suspect?
Yes, I told him. He's pretty groggy
after the anesthesia.
Sam, Toby, you've got a
phone call in the other room.
Donna?
You wanna throw some water
on your face?
I should ask, is there anything
I'm supposed to be doing right now?
-No.
-Anything that Josh's office should do?
-Should I make sure it's farmed out?
-No. I'm sure it's covered.
-You got them on the phone?
-Yes.
-Guys?
-Yeah, we're here.
Sam, I need you to come here and
speak to Nancy McNally about a letter...
... the president was supposed to sign.
She 'll know what you mean.
-And, Toby?
-Yeah.
-They' re still asking about the tent.
- Yeah.
I'm comfortable with a " no comment"
from the Secret Service.
What's this?
They wanna know why the president
exited the building in open air.
-I'll talk to somebody at T reasury.
-I'll do it.
-Let me.
-Someone.
We're in the meeting together.
-Let's go back to the office.
-Okay. Okay.
Can the ships pass inspection?
They'll register in Libya and Panama
so they aren't subject to the OPA...
...which wouldn't allow an
American company to keep it.
I think 20-1 7.
I think 20-1 5. You get the idea.
I think all that's left then
is to dot the T's.
Actually, I have a thing.
I have a thing I was gonna mention.
Just a proposal to throw out there.
When I was a congressional aide,
we had an expression:
" No idea was too stupid to say
out loud. " So here it is. Bear me out.
Instead of buying the ships,
don't buy these ships.
Buy other ships. Buy better ships.
That's my idea.
What's he talking about?
That's a perfectly fair question.
Sam, what are you talking about?
And we have a no-penalty clause
if we pull out before December 1.
But, Sam, we want these ships. This is
as little as we've ever paid for a fleet.
There's a reason they
don't cost a lot.
They' re 20-year-old, single-hulled
VLCC's that nobody else wants.
They'll hit things and break, because they
don't have good navigation systems.
They don't have G3 tank gauging,
EM-5000 monitoring...
...the recommended
electropneumatic ballast.
And yesterday he didn't know the
difference between a ship and boat.
You told us you covered our liability.
Strictly speaking, I did, but there's
a broader liability to consider.
-People drove past Exxon after Valdez.
-We've got PR firms for PR problems.
There's a Suez tanker ready to launch
at Koje lsland in Korea.
Chevron dropped the option,
and it's in the cradle.
Sam, could I talk to you for a second?
308,000 dead weight tons,
carries 2.2 million gallons.
-You can have it for 46 million.
-46 million dollars?
-That's a good price.
-Sam, what are you doing?
-I think I have an obligation--
-What are you doing?
Maybe they want
to buy safer boats.
Are you trying to get fired?
Maybe they'll thank
us for the suggestion.
Knock it off, Sam.
-Look--
-Knock it off.
I'm looking-- Operator, I'm looking for
the number of a law firm in Manhattan.
Here's the thing, I can't remember
the name of the firm.
No, wait, wait, wait!
I just came back from New Hampshire
where I saw this guy and I have to--
Listen, it's a very famous firm
that handled Shearson...
...you must know, okay.
You know what, I'm just-- Okay. Bye.
-That's advertised over--
-1 5 years.
-Pretax?
-Sam?
Fifteen-year pretax amortization?
-Eleven million extra.
-Oh, God.
-This again?
-The money will be spent.
You can spend it now or later,
but it's cheaper now.
-Sam?
-It's the right thing.
Spend 1 1 million extra
on a better boat.
The Amoco Cadiz. 68 million gallons
of crude oil off Brittany, France.
Braer, a Liberian tanker, 26 million
gallons off the Shetland lslands.
The Exxon Valdez, the Aegean Sea,
the Argo Merchant. Look it up.
-They' re aware--
-Spend 1 1 million.
-Enough.
-You don't wanna pay?
Pass the expense to us.
Half a penny at the tank. Here's 5
bucks, 1000 people are on me.
Sam.
Sam, we are in the
middle of a meeting.
Sam, we're not indifferent to the
concerns for the environmentalist.
-Excuse me, Sam?
-Yeah.
It doe'sn't quite feel like
I have your attention.
Yeah.
Yeah. I'm not gonna need that.
Sam? Sam?
Sam, please keep your seat.
-Sam, where are you going?
-New Hampshire.
If you'll just follow me.
-Sam.
-Yeah.
-I wanted to see if--
-How's your head?
Fine. I wanted to see if
you talked to Nancy McNally.
Yeah. She talked to counsel's office.
They'll work on some things.
We're not gonna like it.
You didn't notice,
when the shooting started...
...you didn't happen to notice who
pulled me to the ground, did you?
No.
They pulled me down behind a police
car and my necklace came off.
You talked to Nancy McNally?
Okay.
-C.J.
-Yeah?
-Call Debbie at The Today Show.
-Why?
We said you'd do the
morning shows at 7.
That's not a good--
No, I'm not gonna do any
interviews yet. I'm not.
I'll take care of it.
-Who said--?
-It's a mistake.
-C.J.?
-Yeah.
I don't wanna be this guy.
Someone thought I should
do morning shows.
-I have no answer.
-Who was in charge?
For the three and a half hours
the president was under anesthesia.
Danny, it's a little complicated.
There's the National Security Act
of 1947, there's the 25th....
Nancy McNally, Bill Hutchinson,
the White House Council, they' re on it.
They'll tell me who was
supposed to be in charge.
I wanna know who was in charge.
And we are working on that information.
We're working on it.
Hello?
Yeah?
Isobel, it's 6:30 in the morning.
Yeah.
Excuse me. C.J.'s here.
Thank you.
Good morning, lsobel.
Hello, Roger.
I asked her to be here 45 minutes ago.
-I'm sorry?
-I said, I asked you to be--
-Roger.
-lt was 6:30 in the morning.
I wasn't quite ready for work.
But I am now, how can I help you?
Are you aware that the Golden Globe
nominations were announced today?
I wasn't.
-Am I up for something?
-Atlantis only got two nominations.
For the entire studio. Best comedy
score and supporting actor for the kid.
That's what 20,000
a month bought us.
Roger, I think we put together
a very aggressive campaign.
-Two nominations.
-That's two more than a lot of people.
Are you aware that the new Premiere
magazine list is coming out Monday?
The 100 most powerful
people in Hollywood.
-Yeah.
-Yes, I am.
I can tell you that you' re on it.
Congratulations. It must, you know,
feel good being that powerful.
I went from third to ninth.
I dropped to ninth.
Do you know how that looks? Do you
know how many were ahead of me?
-Eight?
-Lady, you' re--
The movies were bad, Roger.
All of them.
Even the little kid was bad,
but he was a little kid.
He had a couple of scenes,
big eyeglasses, little lisp.
He's going to the Golden Globes.
Know why the New Coke campaign
failed? Nobody liked New Coke.
The movies were bad.
If the movies were unknown...
...I could help you, but they weren't.
They were just bad.
Roger, would you excuse us
for just a second, please.
Sorry I talked to him like that...
...but do you think he had
The Maltese Falcon out there?
The thing is, C.J.,
he's big business for me.
I'll apologize to him, lsobel.
I'll find someone to make him
man of the year.
I'll ask around in Vegas.
He wants you fired.
He thinks you're a smart mouth.
He's gonna pull his business
unless you fire me?
This is never what you
wanted to be doing, C.J.
-You've always felt it was beneath you.
-lt is.
Take me off film and television.
I don't know anything about it, anyway.
I need to keep his business.
I'm sorry.
-You're firing me?
-I'm sorry.
-Out here in the hallway?
-C.J....
-I need someone to call me a cab.
-I'm sorry?
I couldn't get my contacts in and I broke
my glasses getting out of the car.
I can't drive myself home.
I need someone to call me a cab.
Could you call a taxi for C.J., please?
I have to go back in.
It was a bad movie, lsobel.
Yes, I need a taxi for
Beverly Hills, please.
-Hello.
-Hey, C.J.
-Who is that?
-It's me.
-Toby?
-Yeah.
What the hell are you--? Ah!
C.J., you fell into the pool there.
I can't see.
Yeah. Well, maybe kind of try and feel
your way to dry land. You want a hand?
Shut up.
-Avert your eyes.
-What?
I'm climbing out of the pool,
my clothes will cling. Avert your eyes.
-C.J., I didn't come here--
-Avert your eyes.
Okay.
Oh, turn around.
I tried calling you at your office. They
said you were fired. Were you stealing?
Roger Becker dropped from third
most powerful person in Hollywood...
...to ninth most powerful
person in Hollywood.
-Doe's he still make the playoffs?
-They take it seriously.
C.J., Jed Bartlet's
very impressed with you.
He likes the work you did with that
girl's group with the stupid name.
-Emily's List?
-Yes.
That girl's group with the stupid name?
Emily's List. Early Money
is Like Yeast.
-lt helps raise dough.
-I get it.
They raise money
for women candidates.
Early Money is Like Yeast,
it helps raise the dough...
-...for the candidates.
-I really do get it.
-Bartlet's impressed with me?
-Very impressed.
One of the big keys to his game plan
is bringing you on as press secretary.
-He's never heard of me, has he?
-No.
-Toby....
-I'm here on behalf of Leo McGarry.
-McGarry wants me?
-Yes. Come join the campaign.
-How much?
-How much were you making before?
-$550,000 a year.
-This pays $600 a week.
-So this is less?
-Yes.
Toby, doe's he know I've
only ever worked statewide?
Doe's he know I've never worked
on a national campaign?
Yes. It's graduation day.
You really think I can do this?
Yeah.
-ls Jed Bartlet a good man?
-Yeah.
Toby?
Yes.
Let's go in so I can change my
clothes and we'll talk about it.
-C.J.?
-Yeah.
-The house is over there.
-Okay.
One of them was using a 9mm Beretta,
the other had a.357 Desert Eagle.
Ron's saying that these were
the wrong weapons to use...
...for a shooting of this kind.
That's why the injury count
was so low.
We don't know what
the injury count is yet.
Yeah, but his point is....
-Excuse me, sir. You wanted to see me?
-Yeah.
Charlie, the guy the Secret Service
have in custody is named Carl Leroy.
He gives a statement in which he says
that he and the shooters...
...were members of an organization
called West Virginia White Pride.
They tried to kill the president
because Zoey and I are together?
No.
-Why, then?
-Charlie...
...the president wasn't the target.
According to the statement,
the president wasn't the target.
Okay.
Okay, well....
Thank you, Mr. President.
-Dad, I'm gonna....
-Go.
We don't know what
the injury count is yet.
He was supposed to sign a letter?
If the president is going
under general anesthesia...
...he usually signs a letter handing over
executive powers to the vice president.
And the president didn't sign a letter?
-Nope, we blew that play.
-ls there gonna be trouble?
We'll see. T o be honest with you,
I don't really care right now.
Can I just say something?
You know, for the future?
Yeah.
I can sign the president's name.
I have his signature down pretty good.
-You can sign the president's name?
-Yeah.
On a document removing him from
power and handing it to someone else?
Yeah.
Do you think the White House counsel
would say that was a bad idea?
I think the White House counsel
would say that's a coup d'état.
-I'd probably end up doing time.
-I would think.
And what the hell are you doing
practicing the president's signature?
-Just for fun.
-We've got separation of powers...
...checks and balances, and Margaret,
vetoing things and sending them back.
Who wanted me to do
the morning shows?
-I did.
-Why?
The president's not
ready for cameras...
...if it's the vice president, it'll look
like we don't have a president...
...and it's time the White House
comes out.
-I think it's a bad idea.
-Why?
I just....
First of all, I think it's inappropriate
while Josh-- You know, until....
-What's wrong?
-Nothing.
-C.J.
I'd rather not,
but obviously--
-Have Sam do it.
-Okay.
Listen, the letter....
-The three and a half hours?
-Yeah.
I don't know how long
I can dance around Danny...
...and it'll be Danny times
100 by lunch.
-Have him come see me.
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
-Okay.
She doe'sn't want to do
the morning shows.
She's been getting questions about
why the president exited in open air.
They remember that the Secret Service
used to construct a tent or a canopy.
-I'm gonna talk to Ron Butterfield.
-They don't comment on procedure.
I know, but maybe
I can talk him out of it.
I should try anyway.
-You don't have to, Toby.
-Yeah. I should, though.
Okay.
--won the straw poll,
pulling in 48 percent of the vote.
Senator William Wiley drew a poorer
than expected 22 percent...
... but the story this morning
is the 1 9 percent...
... picked up by former New
Hampshire governor, Jed Bartlet...
...who leapfrogged several Democrats
to finish a surprising third.
And we'regonna go now to Governor
Bartlet who's standing by live....
I'm told we don't have the governor
at this moment, so while we try--
-Who can tell me what we did wrong?
-I blew it. What's next?
We didn't have the candidate.
Anybody who answered--
-What's next?
-Toby wants to say something.
-Which one is Toby?
-I am.
-And which one are you?
-I'm Josh.
-What is it you wanted to say?
-Let's get out of New Hampshire.
-Why?
-Nothing to win here.
He's right.
The New Hampshire primary
isn't held in New Hampshire?
-You can't win the primary.
-I'm gonna win the primary.
-Which is why you can't win it.
-You're popular here.
You're a Democrat, elected with 69
percent of the vote. That's unheard of.
All you can hope for
is an "as expected"...
...and there's the possibility
you can embarrass yourself.
-I appreciate that.
-Toby meant in the polls.
I know what he meant.
Hoynes will be in a fight with Wiley
for a second place finish here.
We'll be the only ones
in South Carolina.
We won't beat Hoynes
-We don't have to beat Hoynes.
-We just have to beat Wiley.
Wiley's gonna drop out
after South Carolina?
If he doe'sn't finish higher than third.
-Will we get his endorsement?
-We'll get his money, that's for sure.
-It's for sure?
-Josh thinks it is.
-Which one is Josh?
-I am.
Okay.
So we finish second in South Carolina,
we pick up some steam...
...endorsements, money going into
South Dakota, Vermont, Maine--
Where we get a split or better and
the prohibitive nominee...
-... has lost three of seven contests--
-Half the primaries.
Hoynes'll win the South,
we'll take the North.
-lt will be decided in lllinois.
-lllinois will be High Noon.
If we win in lllinois, we can
win California and New York?
If we win in lllinois,
we're gonna run the table.
That's it then. We've saved people
the trouble of voting. What's next?
-Our point is that it's--
-I understood the point.
We're going to South Carolina
to set up lllinois.
When I ask "what's next,"
it means I'm ready to move on.
So, what's next?
-We're done.
-Fantastic.
Well, I feel bathed in the warm
embrace of the candidate, Leo.
He's really very easy to like once
you get to know him.
-How many people get that far?
-Not that many.
Okay.
Josh Lyman. No, he's not
available right now.
This afternoon he's got a media session
and a 4:00 with finance.
If you leave your name,
I'll give Josh the message.
Thank you very much.
-Hi.
-Who are you?
-I'm Donna Moss. Who are you?
I'm Josh Lyman.
Ahh.
Yes.
-I'm your new assistant.
-Did I have an old assistant?
-Maybe not.
-Who are you?
I'm Donna Moss,
I came here to volunteer and the woman assigned me to you.
-Which woman?
-Betsy.
-You meen Margaret?
-Yes.
-Who are you?
-I'm Donna Moss, I'll be working as your assistant.
-I've got to talk to Margaret.
-Actually, Josh?
-When I said I was assigned to you?
-Yeah?
I may have been overstating it a little.
-Who are you?
-I'm Donna Moss, I drove here from Maddison Wisconsin.
When did your boyfriend
break up with you?
What makes you think my boyfriend broke up with me?
Well, you're too old for your parents
to have kicked you out of the house.
I'm here cause I wanna work for Bartlet.
I'm a college graduate with a degree
in political science and government.
Where did you graduate?
Haa?
-Okay, when I said I graduated?
-Yeah?
-I may have overstated a little.
-Look--
-Look...
-I was a couple of credits short.
-From where?
-University of Wisconsin.
-And you majored in poli-sci and government?
And sociology and psychology.
Ahh,
And biology for a while.
With a minor in French.
-Okay.
-And drama.
You had five majors
and two minors in four years?
-Two years.
-OK, Listen--
I had to drop out.
-I had to drop out.
-Your boyfriend was older than you?
I think that question's a bit
of a personal nature.
You were at my desk,
reading my calendar...
...answering my phone and hoping
I wouldn't notice I never hired you.
-Your boyfriend was older?
-Yes.
-Law student.
-Medical student.
The idea was you'd drop out and pay
bills till he's done with his residency.
-Yes.
-And did you?
And why did Dr. Freeride
break up with you?
What makes you think
he broke up with me?
Donna, this is a campaign
for the presidency...
...and there's nothing
I take more seriously than that.
This can't be a place for people
to find confidence and start over.
-Why not?
-I'm sorry?
-Why can't it be those things?
-Because--
Is it gonna interfere with my typing?
Donna, we're picking up today
and going to South Carolina.
-lf you wanna stay in the Mancester office...
-I wanna come to Charleston.
I can't carry you. I've got a lot of
guys out there not making the trip.
-I'll pay my own way.
-With what?
I'll sleep on the floor, I'll sell my car and
Eventually you'll put me on salary.
-Donna--
-Look.
I think I can be good at this.
I think you might find me valuable.
Go ahead.
Bartlet for America,
Josh Lyman's office.
Yes. I think I'm gonna have
somebody from the press office...
...get back to you if it relates to....
Yes.
Ahh yes.
-Suction.
-Chest tube's clear.
Pressure's holding, 131/65.
-Hey, Spanky.
-Oh, God, what'd I do?
Take a walk with me, would you?
They're taking him off bypass now.
Yeah, I just heard.
I'm gonna head to the hospital.
-You did well on the morning shows.
-Thanks.
I told Leo I didn't want to do it
because Josh was in surgery.
-Yeah.
-You know what the real reason was?
-The real reason?
-Yeah.
-No.
-I think you do.
Listen, C.J.?
The real reason I couldn't
go on the morning shows...
...and give a first hand account of what happened
is, I couldn't remember what happened.
I remember walking out of the building.
I remember somebody knocked me down.
I know my necklace came off...
...and I know a police car
window exploded over my head.
All night long I've been doing briefings using
notes from other people's accounts.
But it's morning now
and I listened to you...
...on the morning shows
and I know what happened.
-C.J.--
-Sam, I think you have my necklace.
I didn't want it to feel beholden to me.
I didn't want it to be like episode of I Dream of Jeannie...
...where now you gotta save my life
in the time-space continuum...
...or you follow me around
with coconut oil and hotel towels....
-Coconut oil?
-I'm just saying--
-I don't feel beholden to you.
-Why not, I saved your life?
Can I have my necklace back?
Thank you.
I'll be in my office.
-Sam.
-Yeah.
Were you scared?
Yeah.
Me too.
Thanks.
-Good morning, C.J.
-Good morning.
We have an update and I can give you
a ballistics report so let's get started.
-C.J.!
-ls he in there?
-No, no, no.
Ron.
Hey, Toby, I heard they're about to
take him off bypass.
Pretty soon yah.
Listen, can I talk to you for a second?
Yeah. Sergeant, I want those people in
the corner back up another 200 feet.
And if they move in again,
handcuff'em to a parking meter.
-How's your hand?
-It's fine.
-You should be home.
-What's on your mind?
C.J.'s starting to get some questions about why
the president's exit wasn't covered in Rosslyn.
Secret Service doesn't
comment on procedure.
Ron, a few weeks after
the president was sworn in...
-...you got a memo about his protection.
-Yeah.
It said he wanted to enter
and exit in the open air.
-He didn't like traveling in a tank.
-Yeah.
It said he wouldn't use
the tent or the canopy anymore.
-Yeah.
-I wrote that memo.
-The president signed it at my urging.
-I know.
It's not right that the Secret Service
be blamed for last night.
I want the Treasury Department
to hand my memo to the press.
-We can't do that.
-There will be a lot of questions.
There are always a lot of questions.
Don't worry.
It's not right. You're the guys--
-Look at your hand.
-It's fine.
-Your hand is not fine.
-Toby.
-Let me go tell them it was my fault.
-lt wasn't your fault.
-Ron--
It wasn't Gina's fault, it wasn't
Charlie's, it wasn't anybody's, Toby.
It was an act of madmen.
You think a tent was gonna stop them?
We got the president into the car,
we got Zoey in the car...
...and at a 1 50 yards
and five stories up...
...the shooters were down 9. 2 seconds
after the first shot was fired.
I would never let you not
let me protect the president.
You tell us you don't like something,
we figure out something else.
It was an act of madmen.
Anyway, the Secret Service
doe'sn't comment on procedure.
Okay.
Good job last night.
Thank you.
Secret Service agents carry
a weapon called a.357 Sig-Sauer.
The agents on the roof shot the two
gunmen with. 726 caliber rifles...
...that are referred to as J-A-R...
...which, believe it or not, stands
for "just another rifle. "
They are made specifically
and exclusively for the Secret Service.
-I wanted to mention something.
-Leo.
This is our fifth press
briefing since midnight...
...and there's one story that
will dominate the news...
...around the world and it'd be easy
to think that President Bartlet...
...Joshua Lyman and Stephanie Abbott
were the only people...
...who were victims of a gun crime
last night. They weren't.
Mark Davis and Sheila Evans of
Philadelphia were killed last night.
He was a biology teacher,
and she was a nursing student.
Tina Bishop and Belinda Larkin
were killed with a gun last night.
They were 1 2.
There were 36 homicides last night.
Four hundred and eighty
sexual assaults, 341 1 robberies...
...3685 aggravated assaults.
All at gunpoint.
If anyone thinks those crimes
could have been prevented...
...if the victims had guns...
... I'd remind you that the president of the
United States was shot last night...
...while surrounded by the best trained
guards in the history of the world.
Back to the briefing.
-She's good.
-Yes, she is.
I'm going to the hospital,
why don't you ride with me.
We're getting good exit polling
in Stark County and Rock lsland.
How good?
We're running 53 to 58
with the undecideds...
...from 72 hours ago
on the 1 2th, 1 4th and 1 5th.
-That's the money.
-DeWitt County.
-Yeah?
-Who you talking to?
I'm talking to nobody.
There's no one at my house.
What's going on?
Nothing. My dad had his chemo today.
These exit polls will cheer him up.
Sam says we got the 72 hour
undecideds in the 1 4th and 1 5th.
Leo, is there any food in
this room that isn't fried?
-lf there is, let's toss it.
-I'm not kidding.
Good exits from
Stark County and Rock lsland.
-How good?
-Good.
Leo, what the hell is this?
Sam's draft of your victory remarks.
"l congratulate my opponent on a
well-fought campaign. "
-You don't want to?
-I want to...
...but I'll call him by his name.
We're back to this?
-Governor, we can--
-I wanna go over this with you.
Excuse me.
It's the exact same crap all over again.
It's amateur hour.
-Damn student....
-You can say it, you know.
It's not like I haven't heard it before.
Your husband's a real son
of a bitch, Mrs. Bartlet.
He doe'sn't like being handled.
I think if he looked around,
he'd see that nobody is handling him.
He's not ready yet, Josh.
He's terrified.
-ls he gonna be ready?
-You bet your ass he will.
In the meantime, you wanna
kick something, kick me.
Toby.
-Got it.
-Here it comes.
With 17 percent
of the precincts reporting...
... we are ready to call the Illinois primary
for former New Hampshire governor....
Hey, hit the music.
-Y es!
-Hey! Way to go!
Now let's get to California.
Leo, we gotta replace this music.
Replace it with some Doobie Brothers.
-Josh.
-You gotta get happy.
You won the lllinois primary.
Come dance with me.
No. Josh. Your father died.
There's a lot of very
happy Bartlet supporters.
We are told the candidate is
in his suite refining his remarks.
He 's due to make an
appearance here any moment.
Just a little under an
hour ago now, this....
Welcome to O 'Hare International Airport.
We 'd like to remind you
this is a smoke-free airport.
Josh?
Governor....
Your father died, Josh.
I can't believe it.
Y eah. Governor, you shouldn't be here.
-What happened?
-Flight leaving for St. Louis.
He went in for his chemotherapy...
...and he developed what's called
a pulmonary embolism, it's a--
-It's a blood clot.
-Yeah.
It went to his heart
and there was cardiac arrest.
Yeah. Yeah.
Governor, you should get
back to the ballroom...
...so you can get on a plane
and get to California.
-He was a lawyer?
-Yeah. A litigator.
Did he like that you were in politics?
I think he would've liked
grandchildren more.
He would've.
He liked that I work for you,
that we were doing well.
He would've liked tonight.
At least his friends and the neighbors
will be spared all the, you know....
He'd be doing some
bragging right now?
Your name wouldn't have come up.
"My son won the lllinois primary. "
Three more hours, he would
have been able to say that.
He'd have been proud.
He was already.
Trust me, Josh, I'm a father.
I appreciate that, governor.
You should really get back to the hotel.
No.
I appreciate your having come here,
but people are waiting for a speech.
They'll wait.
Yeah, they will, but the people
watching television won't.
-I've been a real jackass to you, Josh.
-Well....
T o everybody.
-Toby Ziegler, C.J. Cregg, Sam Seaborn.
-Yeah.
I know what you gave up
to work for this campaign...
...and don't think
I don't know your value.
And I'll never make
you think I don't again.
You gotta be impressed that
I got those names right.
Delta Airlines flight 175 for Kennedy
International now boarding at gate 56.
-They're calling my flight.
-You want me to go with you?
-Go with me?
-Maybe you want company.
I can get a ticket and go with you.
Governor.
California.
You have to go and give a speech
in prime time and go to California.
-I guess you're right.
-You guess?
Listen to me, governor,
if you don't lose this election...
...it isn't gonna be because
you didn't try hard enough.
But it was nice of you to ask.
Thank you, I appreciate it.
Flight 175
to Kennedy International....
They' re calling your flight.
Is he gonna be all right?
-He's gonna be fine.
-Good.
-Leo?
-Yeah.
I'm ready.
Tonight, what began at the Commons
in Concord, Massachusetts...
...as an alliance of farmers and
workers, of cobblers and tinsmiths...
... of statesmen and students,
of mothers and wives...
... of men and boys...
... Iives two centuries later
as America.
My name is Josiah Bartlet...
... and I accept your nomination...
... for the presidency
of the United States.
Josh. Josh, wake up, it's okay.
I want you to wake up.
I couldn't hear you, Josh.
What'd he say?
He said, "What's next? "
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org